so conclusion on your networks I guess
today I saw foundations me you know I
post nice things on Twitter follow me
I'm just kidding alright so again
anytime you have no idea what's going on
just stop me ask questions let's make
these lessons interactive such that I
can try to please you and provide the
necessary information for you to
understand what's going on alright so
convolutional neural networks how cool
is this stuff very cool
mostly because before having
convolutional nets
we couldn't do much and we're gonna
figure out why now how why why and how
these networks are so powerful and they
are going to be basically making they
are making like a very large chunk of
like the whole networks are used these
days so more specifically we are gonna
get used to repeat several times those
three words which are the key words for
understanding convolutions but we are
going to be figuring out that soon so
let's get started and figuring out how
these signals these images and these
different items look like so whenever we
talk about signals we can think about
them as vectors for example we have
there a signal which is representing a
monophonic audio signal so given that it
is only we have only the temporal
dimension going in like the signal
happens over one dimension which is the
temporal dimension this is called 1d
signal and can be represented by a
singular vector as is shown up up there
each
value of that vector represents the
amplitude of the wave form for example
if you have just a sign you're going to
be just hearing like like some sound
like that if you have like different
kind of you know it's not just a sign a
sign you're gonna hear different kind of
Timbers or different kind of different
kind of flavor of the sound moreover
you're familiar how sound works right so
right now I'm just throwing air through
my windpipe where there are like some
membranes which is making the air
vibrate these the vibration propagates
through the air there are going to be
hitting your ears and the ear canal you
have inside some little you have likely
cochlea right and then given about how
much the sound propagates through the
cochlea you're going to be detecting the
pitch and then by adding different pitch
information you can and also like
different kind of yeah I guess speech
information and I figure out what is the
sound I was making over here and then
you reconstruct that using your language
model you have in your brain right and
the same thing Yun was mentioning if you
start speaking another language then you
won't be able to parse the information
because you're using both a speech model
like a conversion between vibrations and
like you know signal your brain plus the
language model in order to make sense
anyhow that was a 1d signal let's say
I'm listening to music so what kind of
signal do I have there so if I listen to
music user is going to be a stare of
stereophonic right so it means you're
gonna have how many channels two
channels right nevertheless what type of
signal is gonna be this one it's still
gonna be one this signal although there
are two channels so you can think about
you know regardless of how many chanted
channels like if you had Dolby Surround
you're gonna have what 5.1 so six I
guess so that's the
you know Victoria the size of the signal
and then the time is the only variable
which is like moving forever okay so
those are 1d signals all right so let's
have a look let's zoom in a little bit
so we have it for example on the left
hand side we have something that looks
like a sinusoidal function here
nevertheless a little bit after you're
gonna have again the same type of
function appearing again so this is
called stationarity you're gonna see
over and over and over again the same
type of pattern across the temporal
dimension okay so the first property of
this signal which is our natural signal
because it happens in nature is gonna be
we said stationarity okay that's the
first one moreover what do you think how
likely is if I have a peak on the left
hand side to have a peak also very
nearby so how likely is to have a peak
there rather than having a peak there
given that you had a peak before or if I
keep going
how likely is you have a peak you know
few seconds later given that you have a
peak on the left hand side so there
should be like some kind of common sense
common knowledge perhaps that if you are
close together and if you are close to
the left hand side is there's gonna be a
larger probability that things are gonna
be looking similar for example you have
like a specific sound will have a very
kind of specific shape but then if you
go a little bit further away from that
sound then there's no relation anymore
about what happened here given what
happened before and so if you compute
the cross correlation between a signal
and itself you know what's a cross
correlation do know like if you don't
know okay
how many hands up who doesn't know a
cross correlation
okay fine so that's gonna be homework
for you if you take one signal just a
signal audio signal
they perform convolution of that signal
with itself okay
and so convolution is going to be you
have your own signal you take the thing
you flip it and then you pass it across
and then you multiply
whenever you're gonna have them overlaid
in the same like when there is zero
misalignment you're gonna have like a
spike and then as you start moving
around you're gonna have basically two
decane sides that represents the fact
that things have much things in common
basically performing a dot product right
so things that have much in common when
they are very close to one specific
location if you go further away things
start you know averaging out so here the
second property of this natural signal
is locality information is contained in
specific portion and parts of the in
this case temporal domain okay so before
we had stationarity now we have locality
alright don't bless you
all right so how about this all right
this is completely unrelated to what
happened over there okay so let's look
at the nice little kitten
what kind of dimensions what kind of
yeah what dimension has this signal what
was your guess it's a 2 dimensional
signal why is that
okay we have also a three-dimensional
signal option here so someone said two
dimensions someone said three dimensions
it's two-dimensional why is that sorry
noise why is two-dimensional because the
information is sorry the information is
especially depicted right so the
information is basically encoded in the
spatial location of those points
although each point is a vector for
example of three or if it's a hyper
spectral image it can be several planes
nevertheless you still you still have
two directions in which points can move
right the thickness doesn't change
across like in the thicknesses of a
given space right so given thickness and
it doesn't change right so you can have
as many you know planes as you want but
the information is basically it's a
spatial information is spread across the
plane so these are two dimensional data
you can also
okay I see your point so like a wide
image or a grayscale image it's
definitely a 2d signal and also it can
be represented by using a tensor of two
dimensions a color image has RGB planes
but the thickness is always three
doesn't change and the information is
still spread across the other two
dimensions so you can change the size of
a color image but you won't change the
thickness of a color image right so we
are talking about here the dimension of
the signal is how is the information
basically spread around right in the
temporal information if you have Dolby
Surround
mono mono signal or you have a stereo we
still have over time right so it's one
dimensional images are 2d so let's have
a look to the little nice kitten and
let's focus on the on the nose right oh
my god this is a monster
no okay nice big creature here right
okay so we observe there and there is
some kind of dark region nearby the eye
you can observe that kind of seeing a
pattern appear over there right so what
is this property of natural signals I
told you two properties
this is stationarity why is this
stationarity right so the same pattern
appears over and over again across the
dimensionality in this case the
dimension is two dimension sorry what is
the likelihood that given that the color
in the pupil is black what is the
likelihood that the peak cellular on the
arrow or the lake on the top tip of the
arrow is also black I would say it's
quite likely right because it's very
close how about that point yeah kind of
less likely right if I keep clicking you
know it's completely it's bright no no
the other pics in right so
is further you go in spacial dimension
the less less likely you're gonna have
you know similar information and so this
is called locality which means there's a
higher likelihood for things to have if
like the information is like containers
in a specific region as you move around
things get much much more you know
independent alright so we have two
properties the third property is gonna
be the following what is this are you
hungry
so you can see here some donuts right no
donuts how you called bagels right all
right so for the you the the one of you
which have glasses take your glasses off
and now answer my question okay
[Music]
so the third property it's
compositionality right and so
compositionality means that the word is
actually explainable right okay you
enjoy the the thing okay you gotta get
back to me right I just try to keep your
life
[Music]
hello okay so for the one that doesn't
have glasses ask the friend who has
glasses and try them on okay now don't
do it if it's not good I'm just kidding
you can squint just queen don't don't
don't use other people glasses okay
question yeah so stationerity means you
observe the same kind of pattern over
and over again your data locality means
that pattern are just localized so you
have some specific information here some
information here information here as you
move away from this point this other
value is gonna be almost independent
from the value of this point here so
things are correlated only within a
neighborhood okay okay everyone has been
experimenting now squinting and looking
at this nice picture okay so this is the
third part which is compositionality
here you can tell how you can actually
see something if you blur it a little
bit because again things are made of
small parts and you can actually you
know compose things in this way anyhow
so these are the three main properties
of natural signals which allow us to can
be exploited for making you know a
design of our architecture which is more
actually prone to extract information
that has these properties okay so we are
just talking now about signals that
exhibits those properties finally okay
there was the last one which I didn't
talk so we had the last one here we have
an English sentence right John picked up
the April
whatever and here again you can
represent each word as one vector for
example each of those items it can be a
vector which has a 1 in correspondent
correspondence to the position of where
that word happens to be in a dictionary
okay so if you have a dictionary of
10,000 words you can just check whatever
is the the word on this dictionary you
just put the page plus the whatever
number like you just figured that the
position of the page in the dictionary
so also language has those kind of
properties things that are close by have
you know some kind of relationship
things away are not less unless you know
correlated and then similar patterns
happen over and over again over you can
use you know words make sentences to
make full essays and to make finally
your write-ups for the sessions I'm just
kidding okay all right so we already
seen this one so I'm gonna be going
quite fast there shouldn't be any I
think questions because also we have
everything written down on the website
right so you can always check the
summaries of the previous lesson on the
website so fully connected layer so this
actually perhaps is a new version of the
diagram this is my XY is at the bottom
lower leverage features what's the color
of the decks think okay good all right
so we have an arrow which represents my
yeah I find it's the proper term but I
like to call them rotations and then
there is some squashing right this
question means the non-linearity then I
have my hidden layer then I have another
rotation and a final squash okay it's
not necessary maybe can be a linear you
know final transformation like a linear
whatever function they're like if you do
if you perform a regression task there
you have the equations right and those
guys can be any of those nonlinear
functions or even a linear function
right if you perform regression once
more and so you can write down these
layers where I expand so this guy here
the the bottom guy is actually a vector
and I represent the vector G with just
one pole there I just show you all the
five items elements of that vector so
you have the X the first layer then you
have the first hidden second hidden
third hit and the last layer so we have
how many layers five okay and then you
can also call them activation layer 1
layer 2 3 4 whatever and then the
matrices are where you store your
parameters you have those different W's
and then in order to get each of those
values you already seen the stuff right
so I go quite faster you perform just
the scalar product which means you just
do that thing you get all those weights
I multiply the input for each of those
weights and you keep going like that and
then you store those weights in those
matrices and so on so as you can tell
there is a lot of arrows right and
regardless of the fact that I spent too
many hours doing that drawing this is
also like very computationally expensive
because there are so many computations
right each arrow represents a weight
which you have to multiply for like by
its own input so what can we do now so
given that our information is has
locality no our data has this locality
is a property what does it mean if I had
something here
do I care what's happening here so some
of you are just shaking the hand and the
rest of you are kind of I don't know not
responsive and I have to ping you
so we have locality right so things are
just in specific regions you actually
care to look about far away no okay
fantastic
so let's simply drop some connections
right so here we go from layer L minus
one to the layer L by using the first
you know five ten and fifteen right plus
I have the last one here to from the
layer add twelve plus one I have three
more right so in total we have eighteen
waves computations right so how about we
drop the things that we don't care right
so like let's say for this neuron
perhaps why why do we have to care about
those guys there on the bottom right so
for example I can just use those three
weights right I just forget about the
other two and then again I just use
those three waves I skip the first and
the last and so on okay so right now we
have just nine connections now just now
nine multiplications and finally three
more so as we go from the left hand side
to the right hand side we climb the
hierarchy and we're gonna have a larger
and larger view right so although these
green bodies here and don't see the
whole input is you keep climbing the
hierarchy you're gonna be able to see
the whole span of the input right so in
this case we're going to be defining the
RF as receptive field so my receptive
field here from the last neuron to the
intermediate neuron is free so what is
gonna be this means that the final
neuron sees three neurons from the
previous layer so what is the receptive
field of the hidden layer with respect
to the input layer the answer was free
yeah correct
but what is now their septic field of
the output layer with respect to the
input layer
five right that's fantastic okay sweet
so right now the whole architecture does
see the whole input while each sub part
like intermediate layers only sees small
regions and this is very nice because
you will spare computations which are
unnecessary because on average they have
no whatsoever in information and so we
managed to speed up the computations
that you actually can compute things in
a decent amount of time clear so we can
talk about sparsity only because we
assume that our data shows locality
right question if my data doesn't show
locality can I use sparsity no okay
fantastic okay all right
more stuff so we also said that this
natural signals are stationary and so
given that they're stationary things
appear over and over again so maybe we
don't have to learn again again the same
stuff of all over the time right so in
this case we said oh we drop those two
lines right and so how about we use the
first connection the oblique one from
you know going in down make it yellow so
all of those are yellows then these are
orange and then the final one are red
right so how many weights do I have here
and I head over here nine right and
before we had 15 right so we drop from
15 to 3 this is like a huge reduction
and how perhaps now it is actually won't
work so we have to fix that in a bit but
anyhow in this way when I train a
network I just had to train three
weights the red
sorry the yellow orange in rent and it's
gonna be actually working even better
because it just has to learn you're
gonna have more information you have
more data for you know training those
specific weights so those are those
three colors the yellow orange and red
are gonna be called my kernel and so I
stored them into a vector over here and
so those if you talk about you know
convolutional careness those are simply
the weight of these over here right the
weights that we are using by using
sparsity and then using parameter
sharing parameter sharing means you use
the same parameter over over again
across the architecture so there are the
following nice properties of using those
two combined so parameter sharing gives
us faster convergence because you're
gonna have much more information to use
in order to train these weights you have
a better generalization because you
don't have to learn every time a
specific type of thing that happened in
different region you just learn
something that makes sense
you know globally then we also have we
are not constrained to the input size
this is so important ray also Jung said
this thing three times yesterday why are
we not constrained to the input size
because we can keep shifting in over
right before in these other case if you
have more neurons you have to learn new
stuff right in this case I can simply
add more neurons and I keep using my
weight across right that was some of the
major points young you know highlighted
yesterday moreover we have the kernel
independence so for the one of you they
are interested in optimization
optimizing like computation this is so
cool because this kernel and another
curve are completely independent so you
can train them you can paralyze is to
make things go faster so finally we have
also some connection sparsity property
and so here we have a reduced amount of
computation which is also very good so
all these properties allowed us to be
able to train this network on a lot of
data you still require a lot of data but
without having sparsity locality so
without having sparsity and parameter
sharing you wouldn't be able to actually
finish training this network in a
reasonable amount of time so let's see
for example now how this works when you
have like audio signal which is how many
dimensional signal 1 dimensional signal
right okay so for example kernels for 1d
data on the right hand side you can see
again my my neurons can I'll be using my
different the first scanner here and so
I'm gonna be storing my kernel there in
that vector for example I can have a
second turn right so right now we have
two kernels the blue purple and pink and
the yellow orange and red so let's say
my output is r2 so that means that each
of those bubbles here each of those
neurons are actually one and two rightly
come out from the from the board
right so it's each of those are having a
thickness of two and let's say the other
guy here are having a thickness of seven
right
they are coming outside from the screen
and they are you know seven euros in
this way so in this case my kernel are
going to be of size 2 times 7 times 3 so
2 means I have two kernels which are
going from 7 to give me 3 outputs hold
on my bed so the 2 means you have our 2
right here because you have two corners
so the first kernel will give you the
first the first column here and the
second kernel is gonna give you the
second column then it has to in need 7
because it needs to match all the
thickness of the previous layer and then
it has 3 because there are three
connections right so maybe I miss I got
confused before does it make sense the
sizing so given that our 273 to means
you had two kernels and therefore you
have two items here like one a one
coming out for each of those columns it
has seven because each of these have a
thickness of 7 and finally 3 means there
are 3 connection connecting to the
previous layer right so 1 the data uses
3d kernels ok so if I call this my
collection of Carolyn right so if those
are gonna be stored in a tensor this
tensor will be a three dimensional
tensor so question for you if I'm gonna
be playing now with images what is the
size of you know full pack of careness
for image convolutional net form right
so we're gonna have the number of
kernels then it's going to be the number
of the thickness and then you're gonna
have connections in height and
connection in width okay so if you're
gonna be checking the currently
convolutional kernels
later on in your notebook actually you
should check that you should find the
same kind of dimensions all right so
questions so far
this is so clear yeah okay so good
question so trade-off about you know
sizing of those convolutions coevolution
occurrence right is it correctly so
three by three he seems to be like the
minimum you can go for if you actually
care about spatial information as Yun
pointed out you can also use one by one
convolution oh sorry one come one like a
convolution with which has only one wait
or if you use like in images you have a
one by one convolution those are used in
order to be having like a final layer
which is still spatial I still can be
applied to a larger input image right
now we just use kernels that are free or
maybe five it's kind of empirical so
it's not like we don't have like a magic
formulas but we've been trying hard in
the past ten years to figure out what is
you know the best set of hyper
parameters and if you check for each
field like for a speech processing
visual processing like image processing
you're gonna figure out what is the
right compromise for your specific data
yeah
second okay that's a good question why
all these numbers why the Kernan has an
odd number of elements so if you
actually have a odd number of elements
there would be a central element right
if you have a even number of elements
there we'll know there won't be a
central value so if you have again odd
number you know that from a specific
point you're gonna be considering even
number of left and even number of right
items if it's a even size kernel that
you actually don't know where the center
is and the center is gonna be the
average of two neighboring samples which
actually creates like a low-pass filter
effect
so even kernel sizes are not usually
preferred or not usually used because
they imply some kind of additional
lowering of the quality of the data okay
so one more thing that we mentioned also
yesterday its padding padding is
something that if it has an effect on
the final results is getting it worse
but it's very convenient for programming
side so if we've had our so as you can
see here when we apply convolution from
this layer you're gonna end up with okay
how many how many neurons we have here
three and we started from files so if we
use a convolutional kernel of three we
lose how many neurons okay one per side
if you're gonna be using a convolutional
kernel of size five how much you're
gonna be losing four right and so that's
the rule user zero padding you have to
add an extra neuron here an extra neuron
here so you're gonna do number of sides
of the kernel right three minus one
divided by two and then you add that
extra whatever number of neurons here
you've set them to zero Y to zero
because usually you zero mean
your inputs or your zero each layer
output by using some normalization
layers in this case yeah three comes
from the size of the kernel and then you
have that some animation should be
playing yeah you have one extra neuron
there there then I have an extra your on
there such that finally you end up with
these you know ghosts neurons there but
now you have the same number of input
and the same number of output and this
is so convenient because if we started
with I don't know 64 neurons you apply a
convolution you still have 64 neurons
and therefore you can use that via max
pooling of two you're going to end up at
32 years otherwise you can have this I
don't know if you consider one we have a
odd number right so you don't know what
to do
laughter a bit right okay so yeah and
you have the same size all right so
let's see how much time you have left
you have a bit of time so let's see how
we use this convolutional net work in
practice so this is like the theory
behind and we have said that we can use
convolutions so this is a convolutional
operator I didn't even define what's a
convolution we just said that if our
data has stationarity locality and is
actually compositional compositional
then we can exploit this by using weight
sharing sparsity and then you know by
stacking several of this layer you have
a like a hierarchy way so by using this
kind of operation is a convolution
I didn't even define it I don't care
right now maybe next class so this is
like the theory behind
now we're gonna see a little bit of
practical you know suggestions how we
actually use this stuff in practice so
next thing we have like a standard
a spatial convolutional net which is
operating which kind of data if it's
spatial it's special because it's my
network right special not just kidding
so special as you know space so in this
case we have multiple layers of course
we stuck them we also talked about why
it's better to have several layers
rather than having a fat layer we have
convolutions of course we have
nonlinearities because otherwise so ok
next time we're gonna see how a
convolution can be implemented with
matrices but convolutions are just
linear operator with which a lot of
zeros and like replication of the same
by the weights but otherwise if you
don't use knowledge non-linearity a
convolution of a convolution it's gonna
be a convolution so we have to clean up
stuff that we have to like put barrier
strength in order to avoid collapse of
the whole network
we had some pooling operator which
Joffrey says that's you know something
already bad but you know you're still
doing that
Hinton right Geoffrey Hinton then we
have something that if you don't use it
your network is not gonna be training so
I'll just use it although we don't know
exactly why it works but I think there
is a question on Piazza I will put a
link there about this batch
normalization also young is going to be
coloring all the normalization layers
finally we have something that also is
quite recent which is called residual or
bypass connections which are basically
these extra connections which allow me
to get the network you know the network
decided whether whether to send
information through this line or
actually send it forward if you stack so
many many layers one after each other
the signal get lost a little bit after
sometime if you add these additional
connections you always have like a path
in order to go back
the bottom to the top and also to have
gradients coming down from the top to
the bottom so that's actually a very
important both the receiver connection
and the best normalization are really
really helpful to get this network to
properly trained if you don't use them
then it's going to be quite hard to get
those networks to really work for the
training part so how does it work we
have here an image for example where
most of the information is spatial
information so the information is spread
across the two dimensions although there
is a thickness and I call the thickness
as characteristic information which
means it provides a information at that
specific point so what is my
characteristic information in this image
with phase RGB image it's a color image
frame so we have the most of the
information is spread on a special
spatial information like if you have me
making funny faces but then at each
point this is not a grayscale image is a
color image right so each point will
have an additional information which is
my you know specific characteristic
information what is it in this case it's
a vector of three values which represent
your RGB are the three letters by the
ball as they represent okay overall what
does it represent like yes intensity
just you know tell me in English without
weird things the color of the pixel
right so my specific information my
character is information yeah I don't
know what you were saying sorry they
collect this information in this case is
just a color right so the color is the
only information that is specific there
but then otherwise information is spread
around as if we climb climb the
hierarchy you can see now some final
vector which has let's say we are doing
classification in this case so my you
know the height and width or the thing
is going to be one by one so it's just
one vector
and then let's say there you have the
specific final logit which is the
highest one so which is representing the
class which is most likely to be the
correct one if it's trained well in the
Midway you have something that is you
know a trade-off between spatial
information and then these
characteristic information okay so
basically it's like a conversion between
spatial information into this
characteristic information do you see
so it basically go from a thing input
data to something it is very thick but
then has no more information spatial
information and so you can see here with
my ninja PowerPoint skills how you can
get you know a reduction of the availa
figner like a figure thicker in our
presentation whereas you actually lose
the spatial special one okay
so that was all one more pouring so
pooling is simply again for example it
can be performed in this way so there
you have some hand drawing because I
didn't want to do you have time to make
it in latex so you have different
regions you apply a specific operator to
that specific region for example you
have the P norm and then yes the P goes
to plus infinity you have the Max and
then that one is not give you one value
right then you perform a stride thank
you sorry jump to Pyxis folder and then
you again you compute the same thing
you're gonna get another value there and
so on until you end up from your data
which was aimed by n with C channels you
get still C channels but then in this
case you get em half and C and enough
half okay and this is for images
there are no parameters on the boolean
how you can nevertheless choose which
kind of pooling I can choose max pudding
average pulling any pudding is wrong so
yeah let's also the problem okay so this
was the mean part with the slides we are
gonna see now the notebooks will go a
bit slower this time I noticed that last
time I kind of rushed are there any
questions so far on this part that we
cover yeah so there is like Geoffrey
Hinton is renowned for saying that max
boiling is something which is just wrong
because you just throw away information
as you average or you take the max you
just throw away things he's been working
on like something called capsule
networks which have you know specific
routing paths that are choosing you know
some better strategies in order to avoid
like throwing away information okay
basically that's the the argument behind
yeah yes so the main purpose of using
this pooling or the stride is actually
to get rid of a lot of data such that
you can compute things in a reasonable
amount of time usually you need a lot of
stride or putting other first layers at
the bottom because otherwise is
absolutely no to it very computationally
expensive yeah
[Music]
players and also like so on the feet
those network architectures are so far
driven by you know the state of the art
which is completely an empirical base we
try hard and we actually go to I mean
now we actually arrive to some kind of
standard so a few years back I was
answering like I don't know but right
now we actually have determined some
good configurations especially using
those receiver connections and the best
normalization we actually can get to
train basically everything yeah
[Music]
so basically you're gonna have your
gradient at a specific point coming down
as well and then you have the other
gradient coming down down then you had a
branch right a branching and if you have
branch what's happening with the
gradient that's correct yeah they get
added right so you have the two
gradients coming from two different
branches getting added together all
right so let's go to the notebook such
that we can cover any we don't rush too
much so here I just go through the
comment so here I train initially I load
the nice data set so I show you a few
characters here okay and I train now a
multi-layer perceptron like a fully
connected Network like a mood you know
yeah fully connected Network and a
convolutional neural net which have the
same number of parameters okay so these
two models will have the same dimension
in terms of D if you save them we'll
wait the same so I'm training here this
guy here with the fully connected
Network it takes a little bit of time
and he gets some 87% okay
this is trained on classification of the
M nice digits from Jung we actually
download from his website if you check
anyhow I train a convolutional neural
net with the same number of parameters
what you expect to have a better a worse
result so my multi-layer perceptron gets
87 percent what do we get with a
convolutional net yes why
okay so what is the point here of using
sparsity what does it mean given that we
have the same number of parameters we
manage to train much more filters right
in the second case because in the first
case we use filters that are completely
trying to get some dependencies between
things that are further away with things
that are closed by so they are
completely wasted
basically they learn 0 instead in the
convolutional net I have all these
parameters they're just concentrated for
figuring out what is the relationship
within a neighborhood neighboring pixels
all right so now it takes the pictures I
shake everything just got scrambled but
I keep the same I scramble the same same
way all the images so I perform a random
permutation always the same random
permutation of all my images or the
pixels on my images what does it happen
if I train both networks so here I
trained see here I have my pics images
and here I just scrambled with the same
scrambling function all the pixels on I
am I my inputs are going to be these
images here the output is going to be
still the class of the original so this
is a four you can see this this is a
four this is a nine
this is a 1 this is a 7 is a 3 in this
is a 4 so I keep the same labels but I
scrambled the order of the pixels and I
perform the same scrambling every time
what do you expect is performance who's
better who's working who's the same
perception how does it how does it do
the perception does he see any
difference
no okay so the guy still 83 Yuans
network what do you guys know that's a
fully connected sorry I'll change the
order
yeah see okay there you go so I can't
even show you this thing all right
so the fully connected guy basically
performed the same the differences are
just basic based on the initial the
random initialization the convolutional
net which was winning by kind of large
advance advantage before actually
performs kind of ish similarly but I
mean worse than much worse than before
why is the convolutional network now
performing worse than my fully connected
Network because we fucked up okay
and so every time you use a
convolutional network you actually have
to think can I use of congressional
network okay if it holds now you have
the three properties then yeah maybe of
course it should be giving you a better
performance if those three properties
don't hold then using convolutional
networks is BS right which was their
bias no okay never mind
all right well I'm good night